Autograph File, B: Guide.
Autograph File, B,
- Bentley, Nicolas, 1907-. T.L.s. to Sir Max Beerbohm; London, 19 May 1934., 1s.(1p.).
  Removed from *63-1056F.
  Purchased with the Amy Lowell fund, Mar 1964.
- Bentley, William, 1759-1819. A.L.s. to [Christoph Daniel Ebeling]; Salem, Mass., Mar 1817., 1s.(3p.)
  C1 10082
- Benton, Joel, 1832-1911. Letters to S. E. Clow:
  - A.L.s.; New York, 15 Feb 1907., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; Poughkeepsie, 17 Feb 1907, 1s.(3p.)
  - A.L.s.; Same, 21 Feb 1907., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; Same, 22 Feb 1907., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; Same, 31 Mar 1907., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; Same, 17 Dec 1909?., 1s.(2p.)
- Benton, Joel, 1832-1911. Letters to [Charles P.?] Everitt:
  - A.L.s.; Poughkeepsie, 16 Oct 1910., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; Same, 18 Oct 1910., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; Same, 20 Oct 1910., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; New York, 9 Nov 1910., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; Poughkeepsie, 11 Nov 1910. (postcard)
- Benton, Joel, 1832-1911. A.L.s. to Henry Paret; Poughkeepsie, 20 Apr 1894., 1s.(2p.)
  With advertisement to sell the House of Seven Fireplaces.
- Benton, Joel, 1832-1911. A.L.s.(postcard) to F. Dana Reed; New York, 8 Feb 1907.
- Benton, Thomas Hart, 1782-1858. A.L.s. to [ ]; Washington City, 24 Aug 1847., 1s.(1p.)
- Benton, Thomas Hart, 1782-1858. A.L.s. to [ ]; Washington, 14 Mar 1853., 1s.(2p.)
  *53M-115. Purchased from Maggs Brothers, Catalog 819, No. 853, 5 Feb 1954.
- Benton, Thomas Hart, 1816-1879. A.L.s. to Edward Cooper; Marshalltown; 7 Jul 1866., 1s.(2p.)
- Benton, Thomas Hart, 1782-1858. A.L.s. to [Duff ] Green and [ ] Jarvis; St. Louis, 16 Aug 1828., 1s.(1p.)
- Béranger, Pierre Jean de, 1780-1857. A.L.s. to Edmond Anthoine; [n.p.] 8 Jan 1831., 1s.(3p.)
  In French.
  *45M-181 (40). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Béranger, Pierre Jean de, 1780-1857. A.L.s. to [ ] Olivier; [Versailles] 12 Aug 1849., 1s.(3p.)
  *42M-499(7). Gift of Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Béranger, Pierre Jean de, 1780-1857. A.L.s. to [Guillaume?] Saulnier; Maisour [?], 22 Jul 1826., 1s.(3p.)
  *45M-181 (39). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Berbrugger, Louis Adrien, 1801-1869. A.L.s. to Francisque Michel; Algiers, 4 Oct 1852., 1s.(2p.)
  Palka autographs, 4591, n.d.
- Berenson, Bernhard, 1865-1959. 5 letters to Philip Hofer;1938-1941.
  Item 1 with extract of letter to Berenson from Hugo Breitner.
  *83M-13. Gift of Philip Hofer, Dec 1983.
- Berenson, Bernhard, 1865-1959. A.L.s. to Agnes Mongan; I Tatti, 9 Dec 1940., 3s. (6p.)
  *70M-91. Gift of Agnes Mongan, 7 June 1971.
- Beresford, William Carr Beresford, 1768-1854. A.L.s. to José Pereira Palha de Faria Guião; London [n.d.], 1s. (2p.)
- [Berger, Anthony, photographer].; Abraham Lincoln with his son, Thomas Lincoln: portrait photograph, [n.p., 1864 9 Feb.], 1 item
  Berger worked in the studio of Mathew B. Brady.
  *44M-98F. Gift of Walter Stone Poor, 1944 12 July.
- Bergh, Henry, 1811-1888. A.L.s. to Charles Nordhoff; New York, 7 Aug 1866., 1s.(2p.)
- Bergh, Henry, 1811-1888. A.L.s. to A. M. Palmer; [New York?] 7 Dec 1881., 1s.(4p.)
- Bergson, Henri, 1859-1941. A.L.s. to Henry James, 3rd; Paris, [Mar 1939]., 1s.(3p.)
  With T.L. (carbon copy) from Henry James, 3rd to Henri Bergson; [New York] 11 Apr 1939. 1s.(1p.)
  *48M-90. Gift of Ralph B. Perry, 29 Oct 1948.
- Bergson, Henri, 1859-1941. A.L.s. to Raimundo Lida; Paris, 30 Oct 1933., 1s.(2p.) env.
  *80M-30. Gift of Mrs. Denah Lida, in memory of Raimundo Lida, 20 May 1981.
- Berkeley, Francis Henry Fitzharding. A.L.s. to [ ]; [London] 25 Mar 1858., 1s.(3p.)
- Berlin, Irving. Alexander's ragtime band. A.MS.s.; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *61M-160. Gift of Raymond S. Wilkins, Apr 1962.
- Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869. A.L.s.to [ ] Schaeffer; Paris, 28 Apr 1867., 1s.(2p.)
  Gift of Mrs. William M. Barber, 15 Nov 1965.
- Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869. A.L.s. to [ ] Schlösser; [n.p., 1853?], 1s.(1p.)
  *56M-99. Gift of George Benson Weston, 31 Dec 1956.
- Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869. A.L.s.to [ ] Jarret; [n.p.] 31 Mar [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *57M-96. Deposited by George Benson Weston, 27 Dec 1957. Later bequest.
- Bern (Canton) Copy of proceedings before the great council of Bern concerning Rudolf von Baldegg and the Hapsburg wars in Switzerland. MS. on paper; [Bern?][1444.], 1s. (2p.)
  With 19th c. transcript.
- Bernard, Claude, 1813-1878. A.L.s. to [Paul Antoine Gratacap, called] Cap; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (31). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Bernard, Sir Francis, bart., 1712?-1779. D.s.; Boston, 10 May 1762., 1s.(1p.)
  Appointing John Gould as Captain of Militia in Suffolk County; and signed also by John Cotton,; Josiah Quincy and others.
  Gift of Mrs Murray A. Potter, 1 July 1930.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p.,n.d.]., 1s.(1p.)
- Bernis, François Joachim de Pierre de, comte de Lyon, cardinal, 1715-1794. A.L.s. to [Guillaume de Lamoignon]; [n.p.] 18 Jan 1769., 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (32). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Bernouilli, Daniel, 1700-1782. A.L.s. with MS. annotation to Louis Jallabert; Basel 16 Feb 1752., 1s.(4p.)
  *86M-64. Gift of David P. Wheatland '22, 23 June 1986.
- Bernstein, Felix, 1878- 2 telegrams (photocopies to Albert Einstein:
  - New York, 29 Apr 1933., 1s. (1p.)
  - Same, 30 Apr 1933., 1s. (1p.)
    *69M-14. Gift of Mrs. Robert Wiener, Dec 1969.
- Bernstorff, Augusta Louise Elisabeth von, countess. A.L.s. to Adam Badeau; London, 24 [ ], 1s.(1p.)
- Bernstorff, Augusta Louise Elisabeth von, countess. A.L.s. to [ ] Motley; [n.p., n.d.]., 1s.(1p.)
- Berr, Michel, 1780-1843. A.L.s.to Baron [ ]; Paris, 4 Dec 1830., 1s.(2p.)
  *57JM-34(2). Bequest of Lee M. Friedman, 1957.
- Berrien, John MacPherson, 1781-1856. MS.L.s. to Edmund Burke; Savannah, 6 June 1845., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-499(8). Gift of Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Berry, Charles Ferdinand, d'Artois, duc de, 1778-1820. A.L.s. (Charles Ferdinand) to [ ]; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(41). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Berry, Marie Caroline Ferdinande Louise de Naples, duchesse de, 1798-1870. A.L.s. (M.C.) to [ ] Podenas; Gratz, 8 Oct 1838., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-499(9). Gift of Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Berryer, Pierre Antoine, 1790-1868. A.L.s. to [ ]; Paris, 2 Apr 1849., 1s.(2p.)
  *49M-187 (33). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Berthelot, Marcelin, 1827-1907. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p.] 16 Dec 1876., 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (34). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Bertie, Norton (?) A.L.s. to: Robert Bacon[1911 ?]Paris, 2 pp.
- Bertrand, Henri Gratien, comte, 1773-1884. A. signature (Bertrand); [n.p., n.d.] Fragment.
  *45M-181(42). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Bertrand, Joseph Louis François, 1822-1900. A.L.s. to [ ]; Paris, 3 Sep 1864., 1s.(2p.)
  *49M-187 (35). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Berwick, William Noel Hill, 3d baron, 1773-1842. A.L.s. to Lloyd L. Winter; Worthing, 25 Sep 1810., 1s. (2p.)
- Berzelius, Jöns Jakob, friherre, 1779-1848. A.L.s.to [ ]; Stockholm, 7 Jan 1840., 1s.(1p.)
  in Swedish.
- Besant, Sir Walter, 1836-1901. A.L.s. to [Dr. ] Paton; [London] 16 [Nov?] 1886., 1s.(1p.)
- Besant, Sir Walter, 1836-1901. A.L.s. to Ernest Alfred Vizetelly; London, 12 Sep 1873., 1s.(1p.)
- Besseler, Heinrich, 1900- T.L.s. to Arthur Tillman Merritt; Leipzig, 7 Aug 1961., 1 letter (1p.)
  Transferred from the Music Library, Aug 1977.
- Best, Samuel, 1802-1873 A.L. (3rd person) to [ ] Varty; Andover, 16 Jul [1855], 1s. (4p.)
  Recat. fr. x5.16F, 25 Sept 1928.
- Beston, Elizabeth (Coatsworth). 5 letters to Constance M. Maxon;1957-1960.
  *70M-107. Gift of Miss Constance M. Maxon, 26 May 1971.
- Beston, Henry, 1888-1968. 4 A.L.s. to Richard Warren Hatch:
  - Nobleboro, 10 Dec 1948., 1s.(2p.).
  - same, 30 Aug 1949., 2s.(3p.).
  - same, 16 Jan 1956., 1s.(2p.).
  - same, 27 Jan 1956., 2s.(4p.).
    *71M-17. Gift of Mr. Richard W. Hatch, 10 Sept 1971.
- Bethan, Sir William, 1779-1853. A.L.s. to Charles Sumner; [n.p., n.d.]., 1s.(1p.)
- Bethisy, marquise de. A.L.s. to [ ]; Chateau de Bressoy, 11 Oct 1871., 1s.(3p.)
  *45M-181 (43). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Bethune, George Washington, 1805-1862. A.L.s. to Henry Brown; Brooklyn, 18 Sep 1849., 1s.(1p.)
- Bethune, George Washington, 1805-1862. A.L.s. to [ ] Clark; Brooklyn, 10 Oct 1854., 1s.(1p.)
- Bethune, George Washington, 1805-1862. A.L.s. to B H Rhinder; Newburgh, 22 Jun 1853., 1s.(1p.)
- Betjeman, John, 1906-. In Westminister Abbey. TS.s.; [n.p., n.d.]., 1s.(1p.)
  Purchased with the Duplicate fund, 20 Oct 1965.
- Betten, Bartlet. A.L.s. to [ ]; Columbia, Cal., 1 Nov 185[0?], 1s.(3p.)
  About the gold-rush days. On p.4, printed poem: Good news from home.
- Beveridge, Albert Jeremiah, 1862-1927. A.L.s. to Oliver Wendell Holmes; Beverly Farms, 19 Nov 1916., 1s.(1p.)
  *50-815. Gift of Mrs. Edward Jackson Holmes, Jan 1951.
- Beveridge, Albert Jeremiah, 1862-1927. T.L.s. to Oliver Wendell Holmes; Indianapolis, 29 Dec 1919., 1s.(1p.)
  *50-815 Gift of Mrs. Edward Jackson Holmes, Jan 1951.
- Beveridge, Kuhne. A.L.s. to [ ] Van Schaick; [New York?], [n.d.]., 1s.(2p.)
- Bewick, Thomas, 1753-1828. A. signature (photographic facsimile); [n.p., n.d.], 1s. (1p.)
  Gift of Miss E. Guerrier, 18 Feb 1944.
- Bewick, Thomas, 1753-1828. Smew or white nun. Drawing by unknown hand, enlarged from Bewick.
  Transferred from Fogg Art Museum, 1955
- Bibb, George Mortimer, 1776-1859. MS.L.s.to Green Waldon; [Washington] 21 Feb 1845., 1s.(1p.)
- Bickersteth, Edward, 1786-1850. A.L.s. to Messrs. Ogle Duncan and Cochrane; Norwich, 30 Nov 1814., 1s.(1p.)
- Biddle, Charles, 1745-1821. A.L.s. to J Smith; Lancaster, 14 Dec 1810., 1s.(1p.)
- Biddle, Charles, 1745-1821. A.L.s. to T Ward; Andalusia, [n.d.]., 1s.(2p.)
- Biddle, Craig, 1823-1910. A.L.(3d person) to [ ] Mann; 9 May 1892., 1s.(1p.)
- Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844. A.L.s. to Henry Eckford;; Bank of the United States, 6 Mar 1826., 1s.(1p.)
- Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844. A.L.s. to Samuel Landon; [Philadelphia] 26 Feb 1829., 1s.(3p.)
- Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844. A.L.s. to Elijah Paine;; Bank of the United States, 13 May 1834., 1s.(1p.)
- Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844. A.L.s. to Joel Roberts Poinsett; Philadelphia, 17 Apr 1839., 1s.(1p.)
- Bidwell, John, 1819-1900. A. signature; Chico, Cal., [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Bidwell, Marshall Spring, 1799-1872. A.L.s. to [ ]; New York, 27 Nov 1860., 1s.(2p.)
- Bierce, Ambrose, 1842-1914? A.L.s. to Messrs. Stone Kimball; Berkeley, Cal., 4 Dec 1893., 1s.(3p.)
  *42M-770. Presented by W. B. O. Field, 23 May 1943.
- Bierce, Ambrose, 1842-1914? A.L.s. to [Robert] Mackay; Washington, 25 Apr 1904., 1s.(3p.)
  *42M-769. Presented by W. B. O. Field, 23 May 1943.
- Bierce, Ambrose, 1842-1914? A.L.s. to [Robert] Mackay; Lyme, Ct., 6 Aug 1905., 2s.(2p.)
  *42M-768. Presented by W. B. O. Field, 23 May 1943.
- Bierstadt, Albert. Autograph.
  German painter in America.
- Bierstadt, Edward. New York, April 20, 1898
  To Mr. E. Van Schaick.
  Engraver.
- Bierstadt, Albert Bierstadt, Albert Note to: Messrs, Hurd and Houghton.
  German Painter in America1830-1902
- Bigelow, Abijah, 1775-1860. A.L.s. to John Locke; Leominster, 10 Mar 1817., 1s.(1p.)
- Bigelow, Francis Hill. A.L.s.to [ ] Lane; Cambridge, 4 May 1911., 1s.(2p.)
  enclosing a. poem "Advertisement" by John Brown and supposedly in the autograph of William Biglow.
  Gift of Francis H. Bigelow, 14 Jan 1910.
- Bigelow, George Newton. A.L.s. to Charles Brooks; Framingham, 1 Jun 1864., 1s.(2p.)
  Written on printed invitation to Quarter-Centennial Normal School Celebration held at Framingham, 1 Jul 1864.
  Recat. fr. Educ MS 1375.
- Bigelow, Jacob, 1787-1879. A.L.s. to Charles Folsom [Boston?] [n.d.]., 1s.(1p.)
- Bigelow, Jacob, 1787-1879. A.L.s. to [Augustus Addison] Gould; [n.p.] 4 May 1850., 1s.(2p.)
  MS.(unidentified hand) on inside 2 pages.
  *47M-373 (10). Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Alfred M. Tozzer,; Mrs. Thomas Barbour, and Miss Gertrude A. Thurston, June 1943.
- Bigelow, John 1861 Minneapolis, May 12, 1912
  To Mr. T. S. Ross, Sec'y Harvard Memorial Society. One of the first to enlist after Lincoln's call.
  Nodate or source.
- Bigelow, John New York, November 15, 1876
  To Mr. Lester
  Author and editor.
- Bigelow, John Letter to: John R. Lowen 1 Nov. 1889
  Author and Editor
- Bigelow, John Letter to: W. Stuart 22 Dec. 1882
- Bigelow, John Letter to: E.W.Walker Co. Narragansett Pier, R.I. 15 July 1896
  Author and Editor.
- Bigelow, John P. State House, August 11, 1838
  To Messers Knowles and Locke.
- Bigelow, John P. Boston, January 2, 1827
  To John Locke.
- Bigelow, Melville M. Bigelow, Melville M. Author
  Autograph
- Bigelow, Melville M. Boston, July 26, 1887
  To Ben. W. Austin.
  Also photograph
  Author.
- Bigelow, Pauline ALS to: Maurice Barrés Malden-on-Hudson, N. Y. March 29, 1916
- Bigelow, Poultney Chelsea, October 6, 1891
  To Allen. Author.
- Bigelow, Timothy, 1767-1821. 2 letters to Timothy Bigelow Sr.:
  - Cambridge, 21 May 1786., (1); 1s.(2p.)
  - Springfield, 28 Jan 1787., (2); 1s.(2p.)
    The second recounts personal experiences in action against Shay's Rebellion.
    *58M-191. Presented by Mrs. R. D. Fay, 2 Mar 1959.
- Bigelow, Timothy, 1767-1821. A.L.s.to Joseph Dennie; Lexington, 30 Sep 1790., 1s.(4p.)
  *58M-192. Presented by Mrs. R. D. Fay, 2 Mar 1959.
- Bigler, John. A.L.s.to [ ]; Pittsburgh, 2 Aug [ ]., 1s.(1p.)
- Biglow, A. A.L.s.to [ ]; Cambridge, 26 Jan 1828., 1s.(1p.)
- Biglow, William, 1773-1844. MS.poem "The Lament of the Weathercock" from the Church in Harvard Square, 1833., 2s.(2p.) env.
- Bignon, Armand Jérome, 1711-1772. A.L.s. to [ ]; Paris, 19 Jan 1740., 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (36). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Bigot de Préamaneu, Félix Julien Jean, comte, 1747-1825. A.L.s. to [ ] de la Saudraye; Paris, 14 Nov 1785., 1s.(3p.)
  *49M-187 (37). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Bikle, Lucy Leffingwell (Cable) 1875- A.L.s. to [Edward Laroque] Tinker; Strafford, Pa., 25, Aug 1944., 4s.(8p.)
  Concerns George Washington Cable.
  *52M-86. Presented by Mr. and Mrs. Larocque Tinker, 4 Dec 1952.
- Bille, Carl Steen Andersen, 1797-1883. MS.L.(unsigned) to Benjamin W. Austin; Copenhagen, 4 Nov 1884., 1s.(1p.)
  With Bille's autograph.
- Billings, Frederick, 1823-1890. A.L.s.to [Sigourney] Butler; Woodstock, Vt., 25 Oct 1888., 1s.(3p.)
- Billings, John Shaw, 1838-1913. T.L.s.to James Westfall Thompson; New York, 23 Nov 1896., 1s.(1p.)
- Billington, Thomas, d. 1832. A.L.s.to Editor, Literary Gazette; [Sunbury, 23 Dec 1827], 1s.(1p.)
- Bindley, James, 1737-1818. A.L.(3d person) to [ ] Philipps; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Bing, Julius. Letters to [W ] Stuart:
  - [N.p.] 31 May 1855., (1); 1s.(1p.)
  - [N.p.] 7 Jun 1855., (2); 4s.(9p.)
  - [N.p.] 2 Jan 1856., (3); 1s.(1p.)
  - Newburyport, Sep 1856., (4); 2s.(4p.)
  - Newburyport, 11 Oct 1856., (5); 1s.(4p.)
  - [Boston] 11 Apr 1857., (6); 1s.(1p.)
  - [Same] 6 Mar 1857., (7); 1s.(3p.)
  - London, 4 Jun 1857., (8); 1s.(4p.)
  - Chicago, 19 Aug 1865., (9); 1s.(4p.)
  - Washington, 9 Jan 1866., (10); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same [n.d.] [1866?], (11); 1s.(1p.)
  - Chicago, 9 Feb 1866., (12); 1s.(4p.)
  - [N.p.] 3 Feb 1866., (13); 1s.(2p.)
  - Washington, 25 Jul 1866., (14); 1s.(4p.)
  - [Same] 15 Aug [1866], (15); 1s.(2p.)
  - Washington, 1 Dec 1866., (16); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same,25 Dec 1866., (17); 1s.(4p.)
  - Same, 2 Jan 1867., (18); 1s.( 3p.)
  - Same, 12 Jul 1867., (19); 1s.(2p.)
  - Boston, 18 Aug 1868., (20); 1s.(4p.)
  - Washington, 11 Oct 1868., (21); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 25 Oct 1868., (22); 1s.(1p.)
  - [New York] 13 Jun 1871., (23); 1s.(2p.)
  - Boston, 5 [ ] 1887., (24); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 5 Jan 1887., (25); 1s.(1p.)
  - [N.p.,n.d.], (26); 1s.(2p.)
  - [N.p.,n.d.], (27); 1s.(2p.)
  - [N.p.,n.d.], (28); 1s.(1p.)
  - [N.p.,n.d.], (29); 1s.(2p.)
  - [N.p.,n.d.], (30); 1s.(2p.)
  - [N.p.,n.d.], (31); 7s.(7p.)
  - [N.p.,n.d.], (32); 12s.(21p.)
- Bing, Julius. A.L.s.to [ ]; [n.p.] 9 Feb 1856., 17s.(18p.)
- Bing, Julius. A.MS.(unsigned); [n.p.,n.d.], 5s.(10p.)
  On "that fearful and terrible iniquity gambling".
- Bing, Julius. A.MS.(unsigned); [n.p.,n.d.], 2s.(2p.)
  On "Jesuitism"
- Bing, Julius.; John Brougham. A.MS.(unsigned); [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
- Bing, Julius.; Rothschild (continued) A.MS.(unsigned); [Yew York? n.d.] pp.21-32 only.
- Bing, Julius. A.MS.(unsigned) beginning "New York presents once in a while remarkable opportunities for testing the qualities of the prevailing schools of histrionic art..."; [n.p.,n.d.], 7s.(12p.)
- Bingham, Henry H. A.L.s.to Erastus Brainerd; Washington, Dec 1885., 1s.(1p.)
- Bingham, Henry H. MS.s. to [William McKinley Washington, 2 Feb 1898., 1s.(1p.)
- Bingham, William, 1751-1804. A.L.s. to [ ] Jackson; Philadelphia, 18 Jul 1793., 1s.(4p.)
- Bingham, William, 1751-1804. A.L.s.to Le Roy Bayard McEvans; Philadelphia, 8 Mar 1799., 1s.(2p.)
- Binney, Horace, 1780-1875. A.L.s.to A. Dickens; Philadelphia, 5 Dec 1853., 1s.(1p.)
  Purchased with the Peabody fund, 22 Apr 1938.
- Binney, Horace, 1780-1875. MS.L.s. to John Kern; [n.p.] 15 Apr 1826., 1s.(1p.)
  Also signed by Ch. Chauncey.
  Also photograph.
- Binney, Horace, 1780-1875. A.L.s. to Theophilus Parsons; Philadelphia, 4 Jun 1859., 1s.(4p.)
  *54M-221 (2). Presented by Mrs. Parsons Plummer, 6 May 1955.
- Binney, Horace, 1780-1875. A.L.s.to William Cummings Wilde; Philadelphia, 11 Jun 1852., 1s.(1p.)
- Binney, Thomas, 1798-1874. A.L.s.to Thomas Raffles; London, 24 Nov [ ]., 1s.(1p.)
- Binyon, Cicely Margaret (Powell). A.L.s.to [Mary (Williams)] Winslow; Streatley, 9 Jul [1943], 1s.(2p.)
  *43M-361. Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, Nov 1943.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. A.L.s. to Florence [Haskell (Corliss) Lamont]; Streatley, Berks., 10 Nov 1935., 1s.(2p.)
  Removed from *52-1862.
- Binyon, Lawrence, 1869-1943. A.L.s.to [John Livingston] Lowes; Streatley, 13 Dec 1934., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-568. Gift of J. N. Lowes, 26 Dec 1945.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. A.L.s. to [Mary (Williams] Winslow; Cambridge, 23 Nov [1933], 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-707. Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, 24 Apr 1943.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. A.L.s. to [Mary (Williams] Winslow; Streatley, Berks., 23 Aug 1934., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-708. Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, 24 Apr 1943.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. A.L.s. to [Mary (Williams)] Winslow; Canterbury, 13 Jun 1934., 1s.(4p.)
  *42M-709. Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, 24 Apr 1943.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. A.L.s. to [Mary (Williams)] Winslow; Streatley, Berks., 16 Apr 1934., 2s.(4p.)
  *42M-710. Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, 24 Apr 1943.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. A.L.s. to [Mary (Williams)] Winslow; Streatley, Berks., 13 Apr 1938., 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-711. Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, 24 Apr 1943.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. A.L.s. to [Mary (Williams)] Winslow; Streatley, Berks., 21 Sep 1939., 2s.(3p.)
  *42M-712. Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, 24 Apr 1943.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. A.L.s. to [Mary (Williams)] Winslow; Athens, 10 Mar 1940., 1s.(4p.) env.
  *42M-713. Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, 24 Apr 1943.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. A.L.s. to [Mary (Williams)] Winslow; Streatley, Berks., 9 Oct 1940., 2s.(4p.) env.
  Appended are transcripts of English earth by Binyon and 12 lines from his translation of Dante's Paradiso.
  *42M-714. Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, 24 Apr 1943.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. A.L.s. to [Mary (Williams)] Winslow; Streatley, Berks., 28 Jan 1942., 1s.(4p.)
  Enclosed with this is a MS. poem of 2pp. beginning Over all this homeland of our fathers...
  *42M-715 (1 and 2). Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, 24 Apr 1943.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. A.L.s. to [Mary (Williams)] Winslow; Streatley, Berks., 14 Apr 1942., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-716. Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, 24 Apr 1943.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. Now is the time for the burning of the leaves [first line] A.MS.s.; [n.p., ca. 1940], 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-718. Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, 24 Apr 1943.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. O when will life taste clean again? [first line] A.MS.s.; [n.p., 1940?], 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-719. Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, 24 Apr 1943.
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943. Taliesin sings to Merlin. A.MS.(unsigned); [n.p., 193-?], 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-717. Presented by Mrs. Frederick Winslow, 24 Apr 1943.
- Biot, Jean Baptiste, 1774-1862. A.L.s. to [ ]; Paris, 25 Jan 1852., 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (38). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Biot, Jean Baptiste, 1774-1862. A.L.s.to Sir Charles Blagden; Paris, 24 Jun 1816., 1s.(4p.)
  A long discussion of the advantages of adopting the metric system in England.
  *56M-35. Purchased with the Degrand fund from E. Weil, Oct 1956.
- Birch, Lionel. A.L.s.to [ ] Oliver; Cambridge, 25 Dec 1931., 1s.(2p.)
  No source, 1941.
- Birch, Samuel, 1813-1885. A.L.s.to [ ]; London, 14 Dec 1867., 1s.(2p.)
- Birch, Thomas, 1779-1851. Drawing: [The battle of New Orleans] Wash drawing, s.; [n.p., 1815], 1s.(1p.)
  Accompanied by engraving made from drawing.
  *42M-1606, 1607. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- Bird, Francis William, 1809-1894. A.L.s.to [ ]; East Walpole, 6 Feb 1860., 1s.(1p.)
- Bird, Frederic Mayer, 1838-1908. Letters to Edwin Francis Hatfield:
  - A.L.s.; Baltimore, ??? Feb 1864., 1s.(4p)
  - A.L.s.; Baltimore, 12 Feb 1864., 2s.(8p)
  - A.L.s.; Baltimore, 22 Feb 1864., 1s.(4p)
  - A.L.s.; Baltimore, 1 Mar 1864., 1s.(4p)
  - A.L.s.; Philadelphia, 19 Jan 1865., 1s.(2p)
  - A.L.s.; same, 7 Feb 1865., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; same, 24 Apr 1865., 1s.(2p.)
  - A.L.s.; same, 29 Apr 1865., 1s.(2p.)
  - A.L.s.; Valatie, 15 Sep 1868., 1s.(3p)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 2 Feb 1871., 1s.(4p)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 7 Feb 1871., 1s.(2p)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 11 Mar 1871., 1s.(2p)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 18 Mar 1871., 1s.(3p)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 27 Mar 1871., 1s.(1p)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 7 Jun 1871., 1s.(2p)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 8 Jul 1871., 1s.(3p)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 25 Aug 1871., 1s.(4p)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 5 Sep 1871., 1s.(2p)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 10 Jan 1871., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 29 Jan 1972., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 2 Feb 1872., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 16 Feb 1872., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Spotswood, 13 Mar 1872., 1s.(3p.)
  - A.L.s.; Waterloo, 28 Oct 1879., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Waterloo, 5 Nov 1879., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Waterloo, 8 Jan 1880., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Waterloo, 5 Feb 1880., 1s.(4p.)
- Bird, Samuel. A.L.s. to Thomas Joseph Pettigrew; [n.p.] 21 Sep 1842., 1s.(3p.)
- Birdseye, George W., 1844- A.L.s. to Thomas Bailey Aldrich; New York, 4 Apr 1863., 1s.(1p.)
  Partly in verse.
  *42M-1413. Gift of Talbot Aldrich, Feb 1943.
- Bishop, Sir Henry Rowley, 1786-1855. A.L.s.to [ ] Lonsdale; Hyde Park, 13 Apr [ ]., 1s.(2p.)
- Birrell, Augustine, 1850-1933. A.L.s. (initials only) to Lady Cunard; Chelsea, [25 Oct 1918], 1s.(1p.) postcard.
- Bishop, William Henry, 1847-1928. A.L.s.to Ben. W. Austin; New York, 20 Dec 1885., 1s.(1p.)
- Bishop, William Henry, 1847-1928. A.L.s.to Lynds Eugene Jones; New Haven, 21 Oct 1893., 1s.(1p.)
- Bismarck, Otto, fürst von, 1815-1898. A.L.s.to [ ]; Friedrichsruh, 28 Mar 1898., 1s.(1p.)
  In German. With English translation.
  Also a photograph.
- Bismarck, Otto, fürst von, 1815-1898. 2 A.MS.(unsigned); [n.p.,n.d.], 2s.(2p.)
  A.envelope to [ ] Bunker; Friedrichsruh, 31 May 1890.
  A.L.s. (facsimile) to [ ]; Friedrichsruh, 12 Apr 1890. 1s.(1p.)
  Photograph, facsimile signature.
- Bissell, Clark. A.L.s. to S. J. Hitchcock; Norwalk, 27 May 1827., 1s.(1p.)